[theme music playing]
[Camia] Friends, she's finally
back in Ardiente.
My daughter, Lily Cruz!
[gasps and laughter]
[Loring] Is that you, Lily?
[Emilia] I want you to witness
Lily Cruz being buried alive.
It's just one phone call away.
[Ivy] Maybe we should postpone
the assassination
of Lily Cruz and Madrigal.
We have to make Arnaldo look good.
That's what he needs right now.
Emilia, stop the operation.
Dad, I already told our men
to proceed with--
Stop it now!
[Ivy] This is a peace agreement.
From this day on, the killing, cheating,
and blackmailing between Diego Torillo
and Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo will stop.
[Arnaldo] For a peaceful election!
[cheering and applause]
[Diego] Your days of torturing Lily
and her family are over.
Do you really think we're done
giving you a hard time?
You're the only one who still believes
we should be scared of you, Emilia.
The moment justice prevails,
you'll get what you deserve.
[Ivy] That peace agreement
is the only thing
stopping her from killing you.
Anna, you need that gun.
You have to protect yourself.
[Jepoy] What about you, Ivy?
After everything that happened,
are you still marrying Arnaldo?
[Ivy] The wedding will proceed.
It needs to push through.
Ivy, you don't have to do that.
I'm here. We're all here.
We can bring the Ardientes down!
You don't have to use yourself
as bait to catch Arnaldo!
-Jepoy--
-What?!
Diego, aren't you going to do something?
Will you just stand there while
Ivy and Arnaldo get married?
-Jepoy.
-Hmm?
[Ivy] Jepoy, of all people,
shouldn't you be the one
who understands
why I need to marry Arnaldo?
I don't have to explain this to you again!
The wedding will push through.
Whether you like it or not,
it's going to happen!
I know.
[unsettling music playing]
There's nothing I can do anyway.
I just need to follow your plan.
And you should.
[unsettling music playing]
Anna, go talk to him.
You hate that Ivy will marry Arnaldo
because until now, you still love her.
You know why I did that, right, Anna?
I know every member of that family.
They're all demons.
When they kidnapped me,
they caged and abused me.
They treated me like an animal.
They tortured me every single day.
I can't let them do that to Ivy
if she gets caught.
Ivy won't get caught.
Besides, you're in no position
to go against Ivy's plans.
Why are you telling me this?
Is it because…
I'm just her friend?
Because I'm just her friend,
I'm not Diego?
And that Diego,
just because I gave way
to let him love Ivy
doesn't mean I'll let Ivy
put herself in danger.
What are you going to do, then?
I'll support her plan.
But I'll find another way
to bring down the Ardientes.
Jepoy and Anna might not understand
but once I set my plans in motion,
they'll realize why I have
to go through with the wedding.
Are you sure about what you're doing, Ivy?
[stutters] Yes I am, Diego.
I'm very sure, and I'll need your help.
[suspenseful music playing]
[unsettling music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
Papa!
You should come and celebrate with us.
Arnaldo's plan was a success.
He's on a roll.
Oh, come here.
Do you still remember this?
Yes, Papa. That's the map of our town.
Yeah.
Remember when we would
campaign at the plaza?
[Julio] The crowd would go crazy.
Everyone was happy and smiling.
They couldn't wait
to hang garlands on my neck.
And the others…
they would wipe off my sweat
as if I was a saint.
[Julio chuckling]
I remember that, Papa.
We provided for our people.
We conditioned their minds…
bought what they needed…
and we gave it to them.
We kept our people happy and contented.
But now…
those same people are the ones
attacking us from all sides…
left and right, back and forth,
upside down.
We are getting hit from all sides.
How did this happen, Emilia?
I know I--
I know I've done…
bad things.
But I only did it to our enemies.
But now…
Diego…
Lily, Camia…
Madrigal.
They won't stop until they destroy us.
But Papa…
we could have stopped this…
if only you didn't listen to Ivy Aguas.
[sighs]
One day, Emilia…
one day, we'll stop them all…
but not in the way you're thinking.
But for now…
I would like you to take care
of one of our enemies.
Kill Jaguar.
[suspenseful music playing]
For the sake of our family.
[ominous music playing]
[sighs]
I'm not really used to fighting.
But when I saw Emilia,
I remembered all the terrible
things she did to you and Ivy.
I felt like I was the one
she hurt firsthand.
Emilia shouldn't have
talked to you like that.
I'm sorry that you got dragged into this.
No, it's fine.
By the way, thank you
for defending me from Emilia.
Anna, I should be the one thanking you.
You risked your life to protect
my daughter's real identity.
You don't know how big
of a sacrifice you're making
just so Lily can continue
her fight against the Ardientes.
I'm also doing this for Nanny Carlotta.
Anna, you can count on my support.
And I won't allow anyone to hurt you.
I'll protect you like my own daughter.
[melancholic music playing]
[unsettling music playing]
JAGUAR TAKES OVER
THE ARDIENTES' TURF
MASKED GAMBLING LORD
FACING THE ARDIENTES HEAD-ON
[Jepoy] Who are you, Jaguar?
I need you in my fight
against the Ardientes.
[tense music playing]
So, you're really going to kill Jaguar?
Can you do it?
[sighs]
That's what Papa ordered me to do.
Your father has given you a lot of orders
but you've ignored most of them.
Something is different now.
For the first time,
he talked to me without mocking me.
I also noticed a lot of changes in you
ever since you started
dealing with Jaguar.
You look more beautiful.
And you're sexier too.
Raul, please.
Are you really doing all this for Jaguar?
[slow tense music playing]
Once I run out of patience…
I'll have him killed myself.
[unsettling music playing]
Go to bed, Raul. I have to make a call.
Arnaldo, do you remember
how back in the day,
even when you were kids,
you and Diego always used to fight a lot?
And you'd always end up winning
no matter what the fight was about.
And that is really what you did
at the last press conference.
You gave him a good beating. That's good!
Thank you, Grandpa.
You know, now I'm thinking…
we should push through with the debate
so you can completely demolish that loser.
Okay. I'm game.
[Julio] This really calls
for a celebration.
Imagine…
Arnaldo is ahead of Diego.
And, of course, my dear daughter, Emilia,
is about to terminate Jaguar.
I've never been so proud of this family.
-Long live, Ardiente.
[ominous music playing]
[Arnaldo] Thank you.
[Marlon] Those Ardientes are at it again.
They canceled the first debate.
But now, they want to schedule a new one?
[Anna] Are we going to do it?
Diego, are you ready to face
the Ardientes again?
I've always been ready.
I'm not hiding anything.
They won't find any dirt on me.
And this is actually a good thing,
so I can finally present
my platform to the public.
But, Diego, they canceled the first debate
because they were afraid
of being implicated
in the murder of Nimfa.
It won't happen again.
Once I find an opening,
even the smallest opportunity,
I will reveal
the Ardientes' darkest secrets.
[tense music playing]
[unsettling music playing]
You can't say no to me, Jaguar.
[phone chimes]
Perfect.
-[screams]
-[gunshot]
Let go of me!
[Emilia] Jaguar saved my life.
So, why would he kill me right away?
A cellphone?
"Call me, my beautiful".
Jaguar's quite the sweet-talker, isn't he?
[Raul] You should know
how obsessed I am with you.
That's why I saved you
from Natalie, remember?
[Emilia] Obsessed?
[Raul] I want to steal you away
from your husband.
[unsettling music playing]
Well, it was nice while it lasted.
But some good things really never last.
Well, not in Poblacion Ardiente.
[unsettling music swells]
Ping!
Jaguar.
And I'm ready to go.
[ominous music playing]
Jaguar.
Emilia.
[ominous music playing]
Jaguar…
Who are you?
[ominous music intensifies]
Don't touch that.
You don't know what's in there.
It might bite you.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Emilia grunts]
Who are you?!
[grunts]
Jaguar.
[tense music playing]
[car engine starts]
Jaguar!
[car engine revving]
[tense music playing]
[car door closes]
There you go.
Hon, this tie looks good on you!
Why don't you wear it tomorrow?
I have a feeling
it'll be your lucky charm.
Why?
Well…
I guess you don't need a lucky charm.
I'm sure you'll wipe the floor
with Diego after the debate.
Is that what you really think?
-[Ivy chuckles]
-Huh?
Is it?
Hon!
Yes, it's what I really think.
And that hurt.
I'm sorry. I just wanted to be sure.
Sorry.
-Sorry.
-Hon.
Sorry.
I was just making sure.
[tense music playing]
[tense music intensifies]
[alarm goes off]
Emilia?
Hmm?
[alarm continues beeping]
[Raul] I set my alarm wrong again.
[Raul] So, you're really going
to kill Jaguar?
Can you do it?
That's what Papa ordered me to do.
Your father has given you a lot of orders
but you've ignored most of them.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Raul?
Where are you? I need to talk to you.
I'm here at home.
Emilia… my love…
What's going on?
Do you know what time it is? It's late.
You know, I need to rest.
I'm meeting some clients tomorrow morning.
So if you don't need me
for anything important…
you should let me go to bed.
Okay, fine. Good night.
Okay, good night.
[tense music playing]
[car engine stops]
[car door closes]
Jaguar!
[suspenseful music playing]
Jenny, where's my husband?
I don't know, ma'am.
Jeez, you never know anything! Get lost!
Let's see if you're here, then.
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[knocks on door]
Raul?
Raul.
Hey.
Where have you been?
Rufo…
I need your help.
Rufo, take me to the mansion now.
Let's go.
[car door closes]
What are you talking about?
I'm right here.
I'm in our house, taking a bath.
Did you just come in?
What do you mean?
We just spoke on the phone, remember?
I told you I was going to bed.
I'm just taking a bath first.
Hold on. What's the problem?
Is something wrong?
Nothing.
Wait up, Emilia.
Don't you want to join me in here?
-No.
-Come on, Emilia.
Hop in.
Come here.
Emilia.
[tense music playing]
[drums playing]
[man] Diego for a new Ardiente!
[chanting] Diego, Diego! Diego, Diego!
I'm okay.
Diego, my little brother. Are you ready?
I think I should be the one
asking you that.
Are you ready, brother?
[chuckles]
I just thought you might
back out like the first debate.
Well, I must admit you're
giving me one hell of a fight.
But I'm confident the people of
Ardiente will still vote for me.
Let's see.
[Amelia sighs loudly]
Hon…
I need to make a call
to the office in Manila.
Okay, sure.
-Excuse me.
-I'll stay here.
Yeah.
[tense music playing]
[cell phone buzzing]
[Diego, whispering] Ivy.
Diego…
Good luck later.
I know you've got this.
For the future of Poblacion Ardiente.
[tense music continues playing]
[people chanting]
Diego Torillo for real change!
You can't help but
be jealous of me, can you?
Ever since we were kids,
you've always wanted what I had.
Mom's love…
Grandpa's love…
and Ivy.
Now, you want to steal my position.
But don't worry.
I'll make you taste
the bitter sting of defeat.
That way, you'll start thinking twice
about pushing through with your campaign.
You know what, Mayor?
Less talk, more action.
Hon…
[tense music playing]
Come.
[Marlon] Batch, don't mind him.
He's acting that way because
he knows he's going to lose.
You've got this in the bag.
Arnaldo's no different
from the rest of the Ardientes.
They thrive in violence and bloodshed.
They don't know how to fight fair.
But today, I'll make sure…
that he loses.
[TV announcer] Live from
Poblacion Ardiente Auditorium…
The biggest face-off that
everyone has been talking about.
The Poblacion Ardiente Public Debate!
[emcee] Please welcome,
our debate facilitator,
the one and only Ka Tunying,
Anthony Taberna!
[cheers and applause]
Good day, everyone.
Thank you for coming here today
for the Poblacion Ardiente Public Debate.
[cheers and applause]
With us today are the contenders
for the gubernatorial post.
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo!
[cheers and applause]
[audience chanting] Ardiente forever!
Go get him, tiger.
[chanting continues]
Boo-yah!
Sir.
-Good day.
-And to you.
And we also have his opponent…
Mr. Diego Ardiente-Torillo!
[cheers and applause]
[audience chanting]
Diego Torillo for real change!
[chanting continues]
Good luck!
We will discuss several issues,
including the problems
being faced by our province.
Our contenders need to explain
how they will solve these problems
should they be elected to office.
Gentlemen, are you ready?
Yes, sir. I'm ready.
But I don't know if my brother,
Diego Torillo, is.
Are you?
[Anthony] Mr. Torillo?
Yes, I'm ready.
[Anthony] All right then.
Let's begin.
[cheers and applause]
We'll have an exciting debate today
because we're going to find out
what's in the minds and hearts
of our two candidates.
But before we begin…
I'd like to remind our candidates
that you have 90 seconds
to answer in each round.
Then, we'll give you
60 seconds each for rebuttal,
and another 30 seconds to
counter the opponent's comments.
Lastly, you'll hear a sound to inform you
that you only have
10 seconds left to answer.
Is everything clear, gentlemen?
-Yes, it's clear.
-Loud and clear.
Very good. Now, here's our first question.
Let's talk about the economy.
Poblacion Ardiente is known
as the fruit and vegetable bowl
of the country.
What projects will you implement
to further improve the
economic status of the province?
I'll go first, Mr. Anthony.
Throughout the whole duration
of my service as mayor,
I've implemented many projects
for my constituents,
which brought investors
from Manila and other countries.
First, I launched
the Export Processing Zone
which was a big help
to Poblacion Ardiente's economy.
"A big help"?
What help are you talking about?
I think you meant the project
was a big help to your family.
There might be many projects
implemented in this town,
but the people
didn't benefit from them at all.
So in my opinion, you can't say
that our town is progressive
when only a certain few
benefit from new projects.
If I become the governor of this province,
I promise to help each
and every one of you.
I will help every resident
of Poblacion Ardiente
set up their own businesses.
That way, not only our town will improve,
but your lives as well.
I believe that the people are the key
to having a progressive province.
So, we should prioritize their welfare.
[scoffs]
-[Diego] Thank you very much.
-[cheers and applause]
[audience chanting]
Diego Torillo for real change!
[chanting continues]
[cheers and applause]
[Anthony] You all heard
Diego Torillo's answer.
After discussing the economy,
let's ask them about
their respective platforms for education.
Mr. Anthony, before I answer that,
let me just give a comment
on Diego's answer.
I don't know why he couldn't remember,
but the whole time the Ardientes
have served this town,
we've been implementing
projects for the poor.
Okay?
But…
I'm not sure why you don't get it, Diego.
Well, I guess it's because
of your lack of expertise
since you haven't held
any government positions before.
Before we can implement
projects for the people,
we first need to have political
and business connections.
But wouldn't it be better
if our lives would all improve together?
The old, the young, the rich, the poor,
businessmen or farmers.
How can we do that?
Through a system
of all-inclusive governance.
We should help the poor,
give free tuition to students,
and raise funds to build
more schools and hospitals.
I believe that's possible.
[ominous music playing]
[Anthony] Mayor Arnaldo?
[suspenseful music playing]
Do you want to comment on
Mr. Torillo's answer?
You're running out of time, Mayor.
[timer beeping]
[buzzer]
Excuse me.
Mayor?
Mayor!
[Anthony] What's happening?
[indistinct murmuring]
-Arnaldo?
-Mayor!
[Emilia] Arnaldo!
[indistinct chatter]
-[reporter 1] Mayor!
-[reporter 2] What happened, Mayor?
-[woman] Mayor!
-[man] Mayor!
Impressive, Mendoza.
Impressive! Perfect!
I'll transfer the money to your account
but make sure to share it
with the woman you hired.
-Again, impressive!
-It's Ms. Aguas.
[reporter] Ms. Aguas, may we
ask you a few questions?
-It's okay. Yes?
-Could you give a statement
regarding what happened
to Mayor Ardiente-Torillo?
Why did he suddenly walk out?
First of all, I'd like to apologize
to Mayor Arnaldo's supporters
because he didn't do well in his
debate with Diego Torillo.
But I think…
it's time the public learns…
that my future husband…
is going through something.
What do you mean? Is the Mayor sick?
I guess that's all I can say for now.
Thank you.
[reporter] Ms. Aguas, a few
follow-up questions.
Please, can you tell us more…?
What was that?! Huh?!
You…
were a disgrace.
were a humiliation.
You didn't even lift a finger
to correct your mistakes!
Thank goodness Ivy Aguas was there
to cover for your inexcusable behavior!
Julio, enough.
No!
He has to hear this.
Do you know that because of what you did,
it could cost you the election?
Do you know what shame you have
brought to our family again?!
No, no, no!
Allow me.
I have to jolt him out of his dreams.
[Julio laughing]
You think you're so good?
That debate…
was supposed to be something
that was your forte!
You were supposed to prove
that you were more intelligent,
that you were stronger,
that you were better.
You were supposed to prove
that you were superior
over Diego in all aspects!
But no!
What did you do?
You turned yourself into a clown!
You know how you looked like?
You looked like an old coyote
with your tail between your legs,
a yellow streak written on your back,
and your foot in your mouth
while everyone was laughing!
[sighs]
I don't understand why you're so mad.
That was just a debate, okay?
I have more opportunities
to win the people's vote!
A press conference!
With a press conference, they'll
forget about what happened.
[scoffs] "With just a press
conference, they'll forget--"
I trusted you!
I trusted you so many times.
But every time, time and time again…
you have always failed me!
Leave!
[tense music playing]
[Julio sighs]
Your son's brain
is down there in his foot!
[reporters] Mayor! Mayor!
Mayor!
Mayor! Mayor!
[door opens]
[door closes]
Sit down.
Grandpa, if you're just
going to scold me again, save--
Please…
sit down, Arnaldo.
[unsettling music playing]
You know…
I have been thinking long and hard.
I have been thinking
long and hard the whole night.
And lately…
sleep has been eluding me.
I would like to apologize.
Now, don't get me wrong.
My apology doesn't come without a price.
Tell me the truth, Arnaldo.
What happened that you had
to walk out during the debate?
Please tell me.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Arnaldo…
I would like to help you.
Tell me what happened.
[shrill tone]
ARNALDO, CONFESS YOUR SINS.
YOUR CONSCIENCE WILL EAT YOU UP.
[Ivy] Why?
-Hon.
-Hon?
-Are you seeing this?
-What?
-This. This. This!
-[shrill tone]
[shrill tone]
[ominous music playing]
[mumbling] She was there.
She was there. I was talking.
And then, she was there.
[mumbling incoherently]
-She was there…
-Huh?
I was there and then…
-I don't even know…
-What?
What's happening to you, Arnaldo?
I don't…
I don't, I don't know…
[mumbling] I don't know
what's happening to me.
[Arnaldo sobs] I don't even know…
I don't even know if you're real!
Huh?
I don't even know if you're here!
-What's wrong with you?
-I'm not, I'm not…
What's happening? [sobbing]
Carlotta, Nimfa…
They're in front of me.
They're haunting me!
They're haunting me.
The people I killed…
They're…
They're right there.
Their faces…
They're alive!
I don't know what's happening.
I don't know what's real anymore!
I don't know if you're real!
I don't know if--
I don't know if I'm here!
I don't know! I don't know what to do!
[sobs] I don't know what to do!
I'm losing it!
-Arnaldo.
-I'm losing it!
-I'm losing it! Is this--
Is this you?!
-Arnaldo.
-I'm not sure anymore!
-Arnaldo…
-I'm not sure! I don't know!
[sobbing] I don't know!
-Arnaldo.
-I don't know.
I don't know.
Arnaldo…
Look at me.
Have you been taking your medicines?
I don't--
I…
I killed them.
Enough, enough, enough.
Enough, my son. Enough.
-I killed them.
-Enough.
[sobbing] Grandpa, I'm sorry.
-I'm sorry I failed you.
-No, no, no.
-I failed you again.
-No, no.
-I failed you.
-You did not, you did not.
-[sobbing] I failed you.
-No, you did not.
I failed you so many times.
I don't know what's happening.
-I…
-It's okay.
-[screaming]
-No, no, no. No!
-[crying]
-No, Arnaldo. No, it's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
-[sobbing]
-It's okay.
-It's all right.
-[sobbing]
-Go and rest.
-Go and rest, okay? Go to sleep.
-[sobbing]
We'll talk again tomorrow, okay?
[Raul] We need Madrigal in our group.
Do you mean to tell me that Jaguar
and that snot-nosed Diego are teaming up?!
Bring me that man.
[Ivy] If you could only see Arnaldo…
All my plans are about to unfold.
[Arthur] Twenty million pesos, Mayor.
Or else, Ivy Aguas will die.
[Arnaldo] Ivy!
I will not be threatened by nobody.
[yells]
Where is Ivy?!
I want to see Ivy!
That she-devil?
She's on her way to hell!
[theme music playing]